

BHARAT SEN
Full Stack Developer (MEAN)

PERSONAL BACKGROUND

8+ years of IT experience in Software Development Life Experience in building MEAN applications using MongoDB, Express JS and NestJS, Angular 2...,9,10,11,12,13, 14,15 NodeJS, creating Web services components of Restful Web services to interact with UI Interfaces using REST API with Node-JS, Express-JS and Creating Ionic Hybrid Mobile App as well with angular based.

My passion is making ideas come to life, be it working solo, as part of a team or leading a team of fellow developers and also provide technical solutions

PRESENT PROFESSIONAL SOFTWARE SERVICES AND TECHNICAL SOLUTIONS

- Currently Working as a Full stack developer with MEAN
- Team Lead(MEAN Stack)
- Operating UBUNTU System
- Also work On Hybrid Mobile App $% \left(1\right) =\left(1\right) +\left(1\right) +\left$
- Provide technically solutions as well on mean things.

AWARDS, HONORED AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Best Team Award 2022
- Team Lead promotion (MEAN)- 2021
- Rising Star Award- 2020
- Senior Full Stack Developer- 2019
- Adopted hybrid app skill with Ionic- 2018
- Full Stack Developer- 2015

CONTACT DETAILS

Home: 9589610545 **DOB:** 05/05/1990

Email: bharatsen123@gmail.com

Current Address: 303/5 Nehru Nagar Indore Pin-452011(M.P.)

Home Address: Nauan tola Unchehra Dist – Satna, Pin-485661(M.P.)

Marital Status: Married

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

Sr. Full Stack Developer & Team Leader(MEAN Stack) AM Webtech Pvt. Ltd ,Indore(Jan, 2021- Present)

Managed the Mean stack specialized team of 3+ Members and educated other web
developers measured the performance of the team.

Total Exp: 8+ Yrs.

- Working since 2020 on Omni channel product(2.0).
- Providing MEAN Stack training.
- Completed over 15+ Enterprise projects and 4 products based on SAAS.
 Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.

Sr. Full Stack Developer AM Webtech Pvt. Ltd ,Indore(June, 2019 - Dec, 2020)

- Joined a new organisation and started working with MEAN Stack team.
- Planned for product & Micro Services with G cloud services.
- Participated Omni Channel product(2.0) and handling individual part of product CI/MI(Controller/Manage Interface) with MEAN technology.

Software Developer (Web & Hybrid App) Quadralyst Pvt. Ltd, Indore(July, 2017 - July, 2019)

- Started on development with latest Angular. NodeJS, Sails framework and also started on Hybrid App with ionic angular based framework.
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications & software with complete accuracy.
- Maximised application efficiency, data quality scope, operability and flexibility.
- Gained about cloud server knowledge and configured from start to finish.

Software Web Developer Quadralyst Pvt. Ltd, Indore(July, 2015 - July, 2017)

- Built the reusable service components using AngularJS 1 services with Object Oriented JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS3 based on the visual designs.
- Worked with back end developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO
 as needed
- Learned about and gained deep understanding of PHP framework(Codeigniter), Map-box and Google Map and Managed, optimised, & updates PHP databases as necessary..

Jr. Web Developer Quadralyst Pvt Ltd Indore(July, 2014 - 2015)

- Collaborated with the team to design, structure, and implement new websites from start to finish;
 undated existing websites.
- Also Started for API/UI with new logic and concept and gained standard level coding.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

- Diploma in Computer Science
 RGPV University (Bhopal, M.P.), Batch of 2011
- Devi Ahilya Vishwavidyalaya, Indore Graduated B.A of 2016
- MP Board of High Secondary Education 2007
- MP Board of High School Education 2005

SKILLS

NodeJS | Express | NESTJS | SailsJS | Angular 2...,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16... | NGRX Store | Angular | Ionic 6,7| MongoDB | MySQL | PostgreSQL | CI/CD | Social media API. | Google Map(GIS) | NODE & Express Micro Services | Third Party API | Payment Gateways. | Angular universal SSR | Socket.IO | HTML | SASS | CSS | BS | JS | JQuery | JSON | Git | BitBucket/GitLab/GitHub | PrimeNG | ChartJS | ElectronJS for Desktop gpp | PeerJs

KNOWN AND WORKED ON BELOW CLOUD SERVERS & BLOCKCHAIN CONCEPT

- G Cloud | AWS | Heroku | Digital Ocean | Render | A2hosting | godaddy.
- Quick Learned & Configure new cloud server.
- Worked on blockchain concept with Team with mongodb.

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

• Carrom board | Chess | Listening music | Learning and creating new things & ideas and also providing technical solutions of problems .

Project/Product History and Specifications

Product Name: Locator CI/MI(Controller Interface)

Summary: It is a Locator Control interface. For all locators By It Administrator can manage everything related to all locators with all features. Locator is a just like google Map feature as per different different business. But here we can change all google map as per business themes and marker whatever locator client wants as per own business

- Duration Year: 2022 Present
- Team Size: 5
- Role Played: Full Stack Developer For CI part of product.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 8, NodeJS, Express, MySQl, Google Cloud Server, CI/CD pipe Line
- Live URL: https://ci.o-c.io/

Project Name: Eco Travels

Summary: This website provides us facility for booking Flights, Hotels and caps in this site no need to go different different site for different things booking flight and caps we can book here many things.

- Duration Year: 2022 Present Live URL: http://ecob2c.benlabs.in/
- Role Played: Worked on just Ui development and functionality.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 13.

> Project Name: CelebsWorldsWide

Summary: This website an online marketplace where the user can hire the celebrity to with his friends, family member etc.

- Duration Year: 2020 2021 Live URL: https://celebs-mean.herokuapp.com
- Role Played: Full Stack Developer, Planned and Managed.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 11, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, AWS Cloud Server.

> Project Name: Stock-Scanner

Summary: This website an Scanning the popular and high Volume coins behalf market cap and also It will be created watchlist which coins will be crossed at least 5 time in the months behalf set market cap and Also it will be deleted which coins had not been crossed.

- Duration Year: 2020 Sept 2021 Live URL: https://mean-
- stockscanner.herokuapp.com
- Role Played: Planned and Managed, Development with Team.

Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 11, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Digital Ocean Cloud Server.

> Project Name: Estimation-Calculator

Summary: It provides budget of Web and App application and It was In-House project. This website an Generating. and ready proposal with PDF for the making web and app application. It calculates proposal as per different different features like Hourly, Resource and Services Wise and also Give CRUD Management system for managing.

- Duration Year: Feb 2020 Sept 2021
- Team Size: 3
- Role Played: Planned and Managed, Development with Team.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Node, Express Angular, MongoDB In-house server.

Project Name: Aquaeko Dashboard

Summary: Aquaeko is electronic device. Whereas it heats water and set/config level. Aquaeko Dashboard website an showing .metadata of Aquaeko Device and other information like how many users are using, Prepare dashboard chart and management system

- Duration Year: 2016 2017
- Role Played: Rest API developer With Team.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 7, NodeJS, SailsJS, MongoDB, Red Hot Server.

➤ Project Name: RedTruck Web & App

Summary: Reditruck Web and App Place the orders like furniture, big boxes, etc. there were many types user (shipper, trucker, driver, fleet owne) it completes all process from place order to delivered and also track order status like place order, pending order, deliverd, cancel order.

- Duration Year: 2016 2017
- Team Size: 5
- Role Played: Full Stack Developer With Team.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, Ionic 1, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, NodeJS, SailsJS, MongoDB, Maze Runner server.

Product Name: AMW-MEET

Summary: It's online meeting platform with the AcknowledgMent now just made POC it's name AMW MEET as a PRODUCT with v1 as like google meet and zoom everyone knows how Does Google Meet work same here our product works but also can share screens:

- Duration Year: 2023- Present Team Size: 2 Role Played: Full Stack Developer For AWM-MEET.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 15, NodeJS, Express,
- PeerJS, SocketJS, Mongodb, GoogRender Cloud Server, CI/CD pipe Line.
- Live URL: https://amw-meet.onrender.com/#/login

> Product Name: CMS For Employees

Summary: The EMS (Employees Management System) is a comprehensive software application designed to streamline and simplify various HR (Human Resources) processes and employee-related tasks within an organization. It provides a centralized platform for managing employee information, tracking their performance, and ensuring efficient communication between the HR department, managers, and employees.

- Duration Year: 2022- 2023 Team Size: 3 Role Played: Worked on just manager part.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 14, ReactJS, Laravel API, Mysql,
- Live URL: http://desktop.amwebtech.org/crm/login/

> Project Name: Blogs and Articles

Summary: It is Islamic website. Here client want to show all facebook articles herself Facebook Page feed and user can like and comment by this side.

- Duration Year: 2022 Present Live URL: https://eqnaa3.amwebtech.org
- Team Size: 3
- Role Played: Full Stack development Ui and API functionality.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 13, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Go daddy server.

> Project Name: Densub

Summary: This website an online marketplace where the practitioners can be hired by the professional dentists to assist them.

- Duration Year: 2019 2020
- Team Size: 4
- Role Played: Full Stack Developer.
- Skills Used: NGX-Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Angular 8, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, AWS Cloud Server, firebase.

> Project Name: Transworld

Summary: The Goal of this project was to build a business with buying and selling accounts. People interested to buy or sell businesses must be able to create a profile and express interest to buy businesses/make enquiries.

- Duration Year: 2019 2020 Team Size: 3 Role Played: Full Stack Developer.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Angular 8, NodeJS, Express, MySql, AWS Cloud Server.

➤ Project Name: Logs-Monitoring
Summary: This website as logs monitoring tools here doing monitoring error and
warning error from selected logs file by this we can upload machine logs files
and pattern with both local/remote and configure as well with remote machine
for auto analyser after that it will fetch logs file automatic if log generate remote

- Duration Year: 2020 2021
- Team Size: 3
- Role Played: API developer, Planned and Managed.
- Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, VueJS, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB,

➤ Product Name: Smart-Axiom

Summary: Smart-Axiom provides big Security Software with Block-chain. Worked on part of smart-axiom product. By our software we can configure/setup small small device with sensor like Nuled, Marvel(MW300), THERMOSTAT Device etc. and Also we can on/off from our system and It takes/sends request from java but for it devices must be connected.

- **Duration Year:** Feb 2017 2018 **Team Size:** 4 **Role Played:** Full stack
- developer with Team. Skills Used: jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS,
- AngularJS, NodeJS, SailsJS, MongoDB, Pie device as like server, Block-Chain with System cache memory.

> Product Name: Beelieving Web & app Summary: Beelieving is an web/app by this user can post prayer for his friends, family member after another user can do just like share system without chatting system and other facility include like create event, group and share photo video etc.

- Duration Year: Feb 2015 2016 Team Size: 3 Role Played: Full Stack
- Developer With Team. **Skills Used:** jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP
- Framework(Codeigniter), Ionic 1, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, Mysql, A2Hosting.